{
    "id": "106cd4d7bb9b461490acbf0fb6f0d1bb",
    "title": "Gap Filling Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "You will not be able to join the course ……………………… you make the payment in advance.",
            "description": "Unless means if not.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "in case",
                "unless"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We have lived in this town …………………………….. ten years.",
            "description": "Use for with duration. ",
            "answers": [
                "since",
                "from",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He was accused ………………………… stealing the money.",
            "description": "Accused is followed by of.",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "of",
                "with"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. the exam yesterday.",
            "description": "Use the simple past when we say when something happened. ",
            "answers": [
                "have written",
                "wrote",
                "had written"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She …………………….. in",
            "description": "Use the simple past when we say when something happened. ",
            "answers": [
                "graduated",
                "has graduated",
                "was graduating"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher along with the students ………………………….. gone on a field trip.",
            "description": "When we connect two nouns with along with, the verb agrees with the former. ",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "When ……………………………… your work yesterday?",
            "description": "In questions we use the inverted word order - that means the auxiliary goes before the subject. ",
            "answers": [
                "you finished",
                "did you finish",
                "did you finished"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………………… for more than a week.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was ill",
                "has been ill",
                "has being ill"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the students ……………………………….. not submitted their work.",
            "description": "Use a singular verb after one of.",
            "answers": [
                "did",
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………………… for you since 9 o’clock in the morning.",
            "description": "To talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present, use the present perfect continuous tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "am waiting",
                "have been waiting",
                "was waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I will talk to him when he …………………………….",
            "description": "When both clauses refer to the future, use the simple present in the subordinate clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will arrive",
                "arrives"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My handwriting is better than ………………………………",
            "description": "Here yours means your handwriting. ",
            "answers": [
                "you",
                "your",
                "yours"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}